<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Minimal Workflow</title>
    <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/authors/admin/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://minimalworkflow.com/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>The Minimal Workflow</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 21:12:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://minimalworkflow.com/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>The Minimal Workflow</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/authors/admin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Normal</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/my-new-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 21:12:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/my-new-normal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a good week back to work. My biggest issue was that i was extremely tired. my guess is that the medications have me feeling this way. The doctor&#39;s office wants me ti give it another week to see how my body adjusts. i am hoping that my energy levels increase. With that said, i can survive either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another adjustment has been that of my new normal. With every twinge from my chest, i tense up. I need to come to grips with the heart attack and make my peace. I dint want these worries to keep causing me issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diet wise, i am doing well. i am watching my cholesterol, fat, and sodium intake. i think i have made a significant reduction. it will be interesting to see what my next set of blood work looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to keep making positive progress this week. i am going to try to add meditation to the mix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Heart after a Week</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/my-heart-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 16:17:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/my-heart-week-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i believe it has been exactly 1 week since my heart attack. i got home from the hospital on Tuesday and i spent most of the week trying to get some rest. Relaxing has never been my forte and this week was a great example. Between trying to come to grios with the heart attack, i think the meds have me messed up. Falling asleep at night has taken me 2-3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on a more positive note, i feel like I have done pretty well eating. Since last week, I have lost 7 lbs. i believe it was as predominantly my cheese weight. i got a heart healthy cookbook as a gift and i am going to spend some time tonight looking at recipes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I will go back to work. I am going to focus on taking it easy on myself. To help combat stress, i am going to use Headspace. if i get too tired, I&#39;ll just come home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of my Heart</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/state-of-my-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/state-of-my-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, November 3rd, I had a massive heart attack. As they were working on me, it was clear that it was questionable if I was going to live. My heart stopped twice before I was airlifted to a hospital with a Cath Lab. I boarded the helicopter not knowing if I would see my wife and kids in life again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole helicopter ride I did not close my eyes for fear of not opening them again. I made sure that the paramedic knew to tell my wife and kids that I love them. My thoughts on that ride were chaotic but I tried to find peace. The pilot opened the window so I could get air, and I thought about how dieing with fresh air blowing on my face might not be so bad. After 30 minutes we made it to the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was immediately rushed to the Cath lab and got a stint placed. It provided relief and the doctor was positive about my prognosis. I was wheeled to the ICU where I finally got to see my wife. She had to drive over an hour to the hospital not knowing if I made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an hour seeing my wife, the chest pains began again. The stint had collapsed. Turns out I was one of the rate people who the common blood thinners do know work. Again, I was rushed to the Cath lab and a stint was placed again. This time it took.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not sleep that night or most of the next day due to fear of closing my eyes. It did not help that my chest wall was blistered due to the shocking used to restart my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All told this &amp;ldquo;adventure&amp;rdquo; lasted approximately 12 hours. I believe strongly that the ramifications of the heart attack will linger for the rest of my life. My only risk factor is high cholesterol, which was diagnosed Monday. My diet will be one of the major changes. Another will have to be stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even as I write about managing stress, I am struggling to go to sleep because I just feel off. I going to have issues with my stress. I am never off. I am always working on something. I need to find the strength and wisdom to change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Farm</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/project/link-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 09:14:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/project/link-farm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-the-link-farm&#34;&gt;What is &amp;ldquo;The Link Farm&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is an attempt to share various links and artcles that i have found professionally and personally helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Earn free bitcoin&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultra Wideband Background</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/ultra-wideband-background/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 21:27:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/ultra-wideband-background/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ultrawide Band&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#f1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrawide band (UWB) signal research is both old and new. Whole experimenting in 1887, Hertz generated the first UWB signals. Hertz created sparks that were radiated though wide-band loaded dipoles. In this time period, short, wide-band pulses were the easiest to create (Win, Dardari, Molisch, Wiesbeck, &amp;amp; Jinyun Zhang, 2009). Interest continued in UWB though the 1970’s. Research in UWB expanded greatly in 2002. In February 2002, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) issued the first authorization for UWB (Andrews, 2003). Similar to Bluetooth and BLE, UWB frequencies between 3.1 - 10.6 Ghz are available for unlicensed use (Win et al., 2009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted previously, the 2002 FCC decision regarding UWB spectrum has created renewed interest in UWB research. Research interest has not translated to significant consumer adoption. It should be noted that unlike BLE, UWB has not become a common place technology. UWB lacks the standard specifications of BLE. This has hampered the broad consumer adoption of the technology (Zafari, Gkelias, &amp;amp; Leung, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the advantages of UWB (Ridolfi, Van de Velde, Steendam, &amp;amp; De Poorter, 2018) include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bandwidth is over 110 Mbps (up to 480 Mbps)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low Cost, Low Power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large bandwidth and the high time resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of particular interest to IoT and Industry 4.0 research is the large bandwidth and the high time resolution. This feature can mitigate indoor environmental factors such as non-line-of-sight reception, multipath, and multiple access interference. Non-line-of-sight reception is due to UWB being able to penetration through obstacles. The penetration is due to the fact that UWB has large frequency spectrum that includes low frequency parts as well as high frequency components (Gezici and Poor, 2009, #97855).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multipath (Figure 1) is a common issue when working with GPS systems. Multipath can be defined as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The term multipath is derived from the fact that a signal transmitted from a GPS satellite can follow a ‘multiple’ number of propagation ‘paths’ to the receiving antenna. This is possible because the signal can be reflected back to the antenna off surrounding objects, including the earth’s surface.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;multipath.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Multipath Example&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Multipath Example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPS measurements (as with UWB) are based on the transmission speed and accurate timekeeping. Signals experiencing multipath are measuring the signal assuming that the signal is traveling in the straight path to the receiver. In actuality, the signal is following the reflected path. This introduces error into the position calculations. The very wide bandwidth and pulses used be UWB mitigate the effects of a dense multipath environments, such as indoors (Win &amp;amp; Scholtz, 1998).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UWB is resistant to multiple access interference. This is interference from other UWB and electronic signals. The very small power spectral densities of UWB reduces the impact of interference (Hu &amp;amp; Beaulieu, 2004).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main disadvantages to UWB include (Kshetrimayum, 2009):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex signal processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bit synchronization time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although UWB is resistant to outside interference, it has the potential to interfere with other electronic signals. WLAN devices working at 5.150–5.825 GHz and 2.4 GHz industrial, scientific, and medical bands are potentially susceptible (Kshetrimayum, 2009). Particularly in a noisy environment, complex signal processing is required by UWB. This processing allows a UWB device to be able to recover data. UWB signals are transferred in pulses. These pulses occur in extremely rapid succession. With intermittent transmission, performance can be significantly impacted (Kshetrimayum, 2009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;1&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; In this document, I use the term Ultrawide Band. In the literature, it is also referred to as Ultra Wide Band, Ultra Wideband, Ultra-Wide Band, Ultra-Wideband, and several other derivations. I use Ultrawide band as synonymous.&lt;a href=&#34;#a1&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrews, J. R. (2003). UWB signal sources, antennas and propagation. public.hofstragroup.com, 15, 439-440.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hu, B., &amp;amp; Beaulieu, N. C. (2004). Accurate evaluation of multiple-access performance in TH-PPM and TH-BPSK UWB systems. IEEE Transactions on communications, 52(10), 1758-1766.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kshetrimayum, R. S. (2009). An introduction to UWB communication systems. IEEE Potentials, 28(2), 9-13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ridolfi, M., Van de Velde, S., Steendam, H., &amp;amp; De Poorter, E. (2018). Analysis of the Scalability of UWB Indoor Localization Solutions for High User Densities. Sensors (Basel, Switzerland), 18(6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Win, M. Z., Dardari, D., Molisch, A. F., Wiesbeck, W., &amp;amp; Jinyun Zhang, W. (2009). History and applications of UWB. dspace.mit.edu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Win, M. Z., &amp;amp; Scholtz, R. A. (1998). On the robustness of ultra-wide bandwidth signals in dense multipath environments. IEEE Communications letters, 2, 51-53.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zafari, F., Gkelias, A., &amp;amp; Leung, K. (2017). A survey of indoor localization systems and technologies. arXiv preprint arXiv:1709.01015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@qikealarcon?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Enrique Alarcon&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/search/photos/iphone-map?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning ArcGIS Basics 2019</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/learning-arcgis-basics-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 13:06:48 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/learning-arcgis-basics-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a long, long, slog, I am finally releasing an updated to my ArcGIS book. The new book covers several new topics including Data Management and Geocoding. I have also included a section on finding a GIS Job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this book is to introduce the reader to Geographic Information Systems (GIS) and ArcGIS Desktop 10.x by ESRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have worked with various GIS lessons, tutorials and how-to books, websites, and other resources. This book is a compilation of all the various &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo; that I have learned. My goal is to help those new to GIS and ArcGIS to develop a solid foundation upon which to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics Covered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1 - Introduction
Chapter 2 - Data Management
Chapter 3 - The ArcGIS Suite
Chapter 4 - The GIS Workspace
Chapter 5 - Project Management and GIS
Chapter 6 - Displaying Spatial Data
Chapter 7 - Selecting Features
Chapter 8 - Symbolizing Data
Chapter 9 - Making A Layout
Chapter 10 - Mid-Term Exercise 1
Chapter 11 - Using Attribute Data
Chapter 12 - Creating and Editing Data
Chapter 13 - Geocoding and GPS Data
Chapter 14 - Coordinate system and Projection
Chapter 15 - Geoprocessing
Chapter 16 - Final Exercise
Chapter 17 - Tips for a GIS Interview&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Data for these lessons can be downloaded from DropBox:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/arcbasics19-all&#34;&gt;http://bit.ly/arcbasics19-all&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Data (1 Zip File) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/arcbasics19-all&#34;&gt;http://bit.ly/arcbasics19-all&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual Zip Files - &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/arcbasics19-folder&#34;&gt;http://bit.ly/arcbasics19-folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bullet Journal: One Week In</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/bullet-journal-week-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 09:14:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/bullet-journal-week-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am one week into using a bullet journal and things are moving along. i am trying to do all my tasks via the journal. i was trying to also do OmniFocus but i found that using both seemed cumbersome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest complaint is my own lack of style. i just feel like my journal should inspire me. unfortunately it does not. i am going to try to improve it&#39;s overall look by using colored pens. The other change i am going to make is to add weekly goals. i did not for this week and i think it would be a good addition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that i will continue to use it for the rest of the month. That way i have a good sample size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo Matt Ragland&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InnovaTN Games</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/innovatn-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 21:25:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/innovatn-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my day job, I am the Director of the APSU GIS Center. For the past couple of months we have been working in collaboration with Google to develop the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://innovatn.org&#34;&gt;InnovaTN Games&lt;/a&gt;. The games will introduce kids to drone flight, engineering, and programming. The event will be in April on the APSU campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we finalize the details, I will post more info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://clarksvillenow.com/local/apsu-google-to-lead-drone-building-workshops-at-riverfest-celebration/&#34;&gt;APSU, Google to lead drone-building workshops at Riverfest Celebration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InnovaTN</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/publicity/innovatn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 21:08:38 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/publicity/innovatn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am pretty excited to tell people about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://apsugis.org&#34;&gt;APSU GIS Center&lt;/a&gt; collaboration with Google for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://innovatn.org&#34;&gt;InnovaTN Games&lt;/a&gt;. The games will introduce kids to drone flight, engineering, and programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we finalize the details, I will post more info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://clarksvillenow.com/local/apsu-google-to-lead-drone-building-workshops-at-riverfest-celebration/&#34;&gt;APSU, Google to lead drone-building workshops at Riverfest Celebration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Bullet Journal</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/starting-bullet-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 23:18:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/starting-bullet-journal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day, i saw a post by &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.amitgawande.com/month-of-bullet-journaling&#34;&gt;@amit&lt;/a&gt; on Micro.Blog regarding &lt;a href=&#34;https://bulletjournal.com&#34;&gt;Bullet Journaling&lt;/a&gt; (BuJu). Seeing his post got me to thinking how i use my notebook. If i am being honest with myself, it is not something that is really helping me. it is just a thing i carry to meetings. Based on this assessment of my current notebook, i headed over to the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://bulletjournal.com&#34;&gt;Bullet Journaling&lt;/a&gt; site to do some research. Based on my research, I had allot to think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I track my tasks and projects in OmniFocus, I have never done a good job of creating weekly, monthly, or yearly goal. Even prior to researching BuJu, I had hoped to use the long Labor Day weekend to create monthly goals for September. A Bullet Journal might be a way for me to set some goals and also use my notebook to better effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it is the beginning of September, I started my BuJu today. I went to Walmart and purchased an Exceed Journal. To it, I added the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future Log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monthly Log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Habit Tracker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will treat this month as an experiment to see if a Bullet Journal helps with my productivity and stress. I will also keep using OmniFocus. I am still unsure if the bullet journal will replace supplement my current system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity and Project Management</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/project/productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 21:46:40 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/project/productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always struggled with the feeling that i could be more productive. Unfortunately, this had caused my to constantly try new productivity systems. with some self reflection, i have begun to realize that the problem me rather that a system. This is my attempt to document as i work to become a better me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Courtney Corlew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My OmniFocus Addiction</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/omnifocus-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 21:56:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/omnifocus-addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;addicted-to-omnifocus&#34;&gt;Addicted to OmniFocus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a the past year, I have been feeling unproductive. The feeling has forced me to look at how is am taking care of my tasks. For almost 15 years that has meant using GTD in some application. I tend follow the general outline of GTD rather than being strict. Over the years I have used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember the Milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toodledo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evernote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trello&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Todoist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OmniFocus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have used OmniFocus the longest out of all the various programs. As I am looking my processes, I sometimes felt like OmniFocus was not really helping me to get where I wanted to go. I decided to try Todoist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todoist had apps for my devices as well as being web centric. This seemed like a definite plus. It was easy to set up and I quickly got all my tasks transferred over. I lasted a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My muscle memory is just strong for OmniFocus. I had already scripted the hell out of OmniFocus and I just couldn&#39;t do the same with Todoist. Changing to Todoist caused too much friction. It was just enough to make more work for myself. I went back to OmniFocus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the experiment with Todoist was a failure, I did realize the problem is me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has made me revaluate hope I am using the software. I am trying to eliminate defer dates and be more rigorous in my review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Andrew Neel&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tactile Map</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/publicity/tactile-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 21:21:44 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/publicity/tactile-map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am really proud of this project. It is so important to assist others. As a geek, it is fun when we can use technolgy to make our community a bettet place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clarksvilleonline.com/2019/08/21/apsu-gis-center-student-creates-3d-printed-tactile-campus-map-for-students-with-low-no-vision/&#34;&gt;APSU GIS Center student creates 3D-printed tactile campus map for students with low, no vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story was covered by News Channel 5 out of Nashville as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newschannel5.com/news/apsu-student-creates-3d-campus-map-for-blind-and-visually-impaired&#34;&gt;https://www.newschannel5.com/news/apsu-student-creates-3d-campus-map-for-blind-and-visually-impaired&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overdrive</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/overdrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 21:00:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/overdrive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;replacing-audible&#34;&gt;Replacing Audible&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past several years, too many of the apps, services, and software I consider indispensable have gone to a subscription model. I recently reviewed all of my various subscriptions and was stunned at the monthly cost. The amount I am spending has gotten to be too much. I have started to look for ways to cut back. Unfortunately, I feel like entertainment services are a good place to cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a faithful audible subscriber for years.  Although I love the service, it is one of my most costly subs at $15 a month. I started to search for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across a review of Overdrive and thought to give it a try. Overdrive allows me to checkout ebooks and addio books via my local library. In the month I have been using the app. I have been pleasantly surprised. There is a wide selection of both audio and ebooks available. The books I have listened to have been of equal quality to what I was used to on Audible. The Overdrive app, loke the Audible app, allows me to speed the playbay. This is a function that I consider essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only &amp;ldquo;complaint&amp;rdquo; I have is the fact that many popular ebooks and auduos have waiting lists. It is not the apps fault, it is a limit on the library&#39;s digital subscription. Overdrive has a feature to place a book on hold, estimate your wait time, and check the book out for you when it becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overdrive has made it to my home screen. i cannot recommend it enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Professional Projects</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/project/professional-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 12:56:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/project/professional-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Professional Projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have had the blessings to work on a variety of projects. I have worked on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GIS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environmental&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of GIS, I have self-taught for the other topics. It has been an interesting ride. The projects listed here are some of the projects I have worked on that others might find of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Southern Border</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/our-southern-border/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 22:18:20 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/our-southern-border/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-this-who-we-now-are&#34;&gt;Is This Who We Now Are?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw this headline this week &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2019-08-15/children-border-sanitary-conditions-flores-agreement-9th-circuit&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Court upholds ruling that children held at border must have adequate food, bedding, sanitation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. Intellectually I knew thing were bad in the detention facilities. The fact that a judge has to order the government to provide clean water, food, and sanitary conditions is reprehensible. I have no faith that this order is being followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am ashamed that this is where we are at as a country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Majkl Velner on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers and Issues in Additive Manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/dissertation-and-additive-manufacturing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 20:43:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/dissertation-and-additive-manufacturing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;barriers-and-issues-in-additive-manufacturing&#34;&gt;Barriers and Issues in Additive Manufacturing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reviewing various literature regarding additive manufacturing, there are several issues regarding wide-spread adoption in the aerospace, automotive and biomedical industries. The key issues can be summarized as making, material, metrology, and market (Tofail et al., 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of particular interest is metrology. According to (Muelaner, 2017), metrology is defined as the science of measurement. The literature refers to metrology as the various measurements required for quality control and assurance (Townsend, Senin, Blunt, Leach, &amp;amp; Taylor, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, the metrology processes can be classified as two types, in situ and off line. In situ measurements are those collected and analyzed in the build chamber. Off line measurements are those that are collected in the chamber and analyzed off site. Generally, in situ analysis is non-destructive but is not as thorough as the more comprehensive and destructive off site measurements (Tofail et al., 2018). Basically in situ is instant but limited and off site is slow, destructive, and comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the literature, the metrology issues that are barriers to widespread adoption (Tofail et al., 2018) can be summarized as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Need for real time in line quality control and assurance
• Process monitoring and control towards optimization
• High level of customization of the techniques for in-situ measurements
• High accuracy and measurement processing speeds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the outlined issues, I believe that there are two possible paths for my dissertation, machine learning and image rectification. In the current process, imagery is captured in situ and analyzed off site. Machine learning, more specifically, image recognition, offered a possible path to quick, near real-time analysis. A project would include the development of a training datasets, ML model selection, model tuning, and experimentation. A more expansive and detailed proposal can be developed if data is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second possible project would be based on the GIS process of image rectification. In GIS, image rectification is the process of manipulating aerial or satellite imagery to accurately represent the Earth[’s surface. Basically, a pixel on an image represents a discrete point (coordinate) on the Earth. I believe that is might be interesting to look at the possibility of using similar techniques to capture images of the additive build process and be able to take measurements as the item is being printed. The experimental part of the project would be the development of a camera configuration and rectification process to take the level of accurate images needed for additive manufacturing. This idea is very speculative. I do believe that I could accomplish much of the data collection needed with the prosumer 3D printers that I have access to on a daily basis. Cameras maybe an issue, although I would be tempted to try a mobile device as a camera system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the two ideas, I am more drawn to the first. I feel that this project could have concrete implications for additive manufacturing. Although interesting, I believe the second project is entirely speculative on my part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muelaner, J. (2017). An Introduction to Metrology and Quality in Manufacturing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://new.engineering.com/story/an-introduction-to-metrology-and-quality-in-manufacturing&#34;&gt;https://new.engineering.com/story/an-introduction-to-metrology-and-quality-in-manufacturing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tofail, S. A. M., Koumoulos, E. P., Bandyopadhyay, A., Bose, S., O’Donoghue, L., &amp;amp; Charitidis, C. (2018). Additive manufacturing: scientific and technological challenges, market uptake and opportunities. Materials Today, 21(1), 22-37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Townsend, A., Senin, N., Blunt, L., Leach, R. K., &amp;amp; Taylor, J. S. (2016). Surface texture metrology for metal additive manufacturing: a review. Precision Engineering, 46, 34-47.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArcBasics</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/project/arcbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 17:51:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/project/arcbasics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-purpose-of-arcbasics&#34;&gt;The Purpose of ArcBasics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this book is to introduce the reader to Geographic Information Systems (GIS) and ArcGIS Desktop 10.x by ESRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have worked with various GIS lessons, tutorials and how-to books, websites, and other resources. This book is a compilation of all the various &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo; that I have learned. My goal is to help those new to GIS and ArcGIS to develop a solid foundation upon which to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topics-covered&#34;&gt;Topics Covered:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1 - Introduction
Chapter 2 - Data Management
Chapter 3 - The ArcGIS Suite
Chapter 4 - The GIS Workspace
Chapter 5 - Project Management and GIS
Chapter 6 - Displaying Spatial Data
Chapter 7 - Selecting Features
Chapter 8 - Symbolizing Data
Chapter 9 - Making A Layout
Chapter 10 - Mid-Term Exercise 1
Chapter 11 - Using Attribute Data
Chapter 12 - Creating and Editing Data
Chapter 13 - Geocoding and GPS Data
Chapter 14 - Coordinate system and Projection
Chapter 15 - Geoprocessing
Chapter 16 - Final Exercise
Chapter 17 - Tips for a GIS Interview&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Tahoe: 2019</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In July 2019, my family and I visited South Lake Tahoe, CA. Here are the pictures I took.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0211-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0211-1_huf2d4aec34eaada6e4497ae863b26b2c0_5706006_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0212-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0212-1_hu77e770bd0c5c6ee6345d8090761dc2e6_2538275_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0213-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0213-1_huceb8536e0ec9d85effb6776dba133e0f_4202603_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0214-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0214-1_huceb8536e0ec9d85effb6776dba133e0f_4164916_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0215-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0215-1_huceb8536e0ec9d85effb6776dba133e0f_3710289_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0216-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0216-1_huceb8536e0ec9d85effb6776dba133e0f_2416834_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0223-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0223-1_hu588c5514948307f33d4af1030a322206_4798872_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0236-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0236-1_hu9d6cb9f1fcfc24777d040c51c2904a6d_4860409_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0237-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0237-1_hu1711b4acfd9a6e705edae7cc9cc65c12_3508327_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0239-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0239-1_hub54d5d8182ae1d982a8c4e2d9c20061a_1999144_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0240-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0240-1_hub6d437c46a2a1ef60934f07535a9b6be_3343553_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0241-1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/IMG_0241-1_hu86143ccbb208b5e4f3fe22b072721803_3525871_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/firstpic.jpeg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/firstpic_hu42d614374aac9e9885f80e2c1cbea60f_3898183_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/reno1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/reno1_hu6eee95ef10e4a60a937e3a8f5ddacc01_517626_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/reno2.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/reno2_hu5f1973509410eddcc33cf738b9a8c060_540400_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/smokey.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://minimalworkflow.com/post/lake-tahoe-2019/gallery/smokey_hu3c8fa9bca859f2de3c97cca1449a07ca_310709_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Workflow</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/hugo-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 20:00:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/hugo-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently returned to keeping a blog. It has always been easy for me to start a blog but hard for me to keep it going. I have tried various CMS, including Wordpress, Drupal, Jekell, Octopress, and Hugo. My current favorite is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I find it minimal, fast, and easy to use. My only real complaint is the fact that I needed to publish from my laptop. It turns out that is no longer the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By utilizing Hugo, Github, and Netlify, i can use a pipeline and publish automatically. Whenever I push an update to GitHub, Netlify will automatically rebuild the site. This has led me to create a new iOS workflow for myself. I can access the code for my site using Working Copy (WC) on my iOS devices. The content can be edited directly in WC but that can lead to issues. i have found it difficult to remember the needed frontmatter for new content. To solve this issue, I create several draft pieces of content. These serve as the basis for new posts. I still manage the code in WC but edit in Texttastic. The app Textastic allows me to duplicate a template and edit it. Once I am done in Textastic, I go back to WC and commit and push changes. The site will then rebuild.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
