<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>apps | The Minimal Workflow</title>
    <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/categories/apps/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://minimalworkflow.com/categories/apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>apps</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 21:00:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://minimalworkflow.com/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>apps</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/categories/apps/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overdrive</title>
      <link>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/overdrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 21:00:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://minimalworkflow.com/post/overdrive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;replacing-audible&#34;&gt;Replacing Audible&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past several years, too many of the apps, services, and software I consider indispensable have gone to a subscription model. I recently reviewed all of my various subscriptions and was stunned at the monthly cost. The amount I am spending has gotten to be too much. I have started to look for ways to cut back. Unfortunately, I feel like entertainment services are a good place to cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a faithful audible subscriber for years.  Although I love the service, it is one of my most costly subs at $15 a month. I started to search for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across a review of Overdrive and thought to give it a try. Overdrive allows me to checkout ebooks and addio books via my local library. In the month I have been using the app. I have been pleasantly surprised. There is a wide selection of both audio and ebooks available. The books I have listened to have been of equal quality to what I was used to on Audible. The Overdrive app, loke the Audible app, allows me to speed the playbay. This is a function that I consider essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only &amp;ldquo;complaint&amp;rdquo; I have is the fact that many popular ebooks and auduos have waiting lists. It is not the apps fault, it is a limit on the library&#39;s digital subscription. Overdrive has a feature to place a book on hold, estimate your wait time, and check the book out for you when it becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overdrive has made it to my home screen. i cannot recommend it enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
